Guide to the Picture File, 1700s-1980s and undated RL.01025
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Geographic Series, 1700s-1980s; 1
  - North Carolina, 39
    - [Durham] North Carolina Mutual and Provident Association Buildings, 1900s, 1 black-and-white photograph and 2 card photographs (Box 7, Folder M239)
    - [Durham] Old Courthouse, 1900s, black-and-white photograph (Box 7, Folder M240)
    - [Durham] Pearl Cotton Mills, 1900s, card photograph (Box 7, Folder M241)
    - [Durham] Poe, Clarence Talton, Sr. Homes and family, 1900s and undated, 1 card photograph and 1 black-and-white photograph (Box 40)
    - [Durham] Southern Conservatory of Music, undated, card photograph (Box 40)
    - [Durham] "S. R. Carrington's Bar and other buildings at the corner of Depot and Mangum Sts," 1800s, card photograph (Box 7, Folder M242)
    - [Durham] Street Scenes, circa 1900, 3 black-and-white photographs (Box 7, Folder M243.2)
    - [Durham] Street Scenes, circa 1900-1905, 6 black-and-white photographs (Box 7, Folder M243.1)
    - [Durham] The Citizen's National Bank, undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 7, Folder M227)
    - [Durham] Trinity Methodist Church, dedicated April 27, 1887, 1900s, black-and-white photograph (Box 44)
    - [Durham] Trinity Park School Class of 1905, 1906, 1908, 3 black-and-white photos (Oversize-folder 30)
      1905 item is broken.
    - [Durham] Various Views, 1900s, 2 card photographs and 1 black-and-white photograph (Box 7, Folder M245)
    - [Durham] W. Duke and Son's Co. Factory, 1901 Sept. 14-15, card photograph (Box 40)
      The factory is draped in mourning for the assassinated President McKinley.
    - [Durham] W. Duke, Sons and Co.'s Factory, 1883, card photograph (Box 7, Folder M249)
    - [Durham] Water Works, 1900s, 2 black-and-white photographs (Box 7, Folder M246)
      Photographs include descriptions on the back.
    - [Durham] Watts Hospital, 1915, black-and-white photograph (Box 7, Folder M248)
    - [Durham] Watts, George Washington -- Home, undated, 17 black-and-white photographs (Box 7, Folder M247)
    - [Durham] West Chapel Hill Street, 1925 Oct. 1, black-and-white photograph (Box 40)
    - [Durham] West Durham School Classes, undated, 2 card photographs (Box 7, Folder M250)
    - [Durham] Wright, Richard Harvey -- Home, undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 8, Folder M251)
      Includes note identifying previous owner as Edward James Parrish.
    - [Fayetteville] "Arsenal at Fayetteville," 1865 Mar. 11 (Box 8, Folder M261)
      Photograph of a sketch. Negative available. "Historical Department N.C. Division U.D.C."
    - [Fayetteville] "View Of Fayetteville," undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 8, Folder M253)
      Photograph of a lithograph.
    - [Franklinville] "Old free school Academy," 1904 Dec. 23 (Box 8, Folder M261)
    - [Greenville] East Carolina Training School for Teachers, undated, postcard (Box 8, Folder M254)
    - [Halifax County] Prospect Hill, near Airlie, undated, 8 black-and-white photographs (Box 8, Folder M255)
      See Johnston and Waterman, The Early Architecture of North Carolina, pages 113-120.
    - [Hickory] "New M. E. Church South," undated (Box 8, Folder M261)
    - [High Point] "Inn of Nathan Hunt, Jr.," 1936 Oct. (Box 8, Folder M261)
    - [High Point] "Springfield Museum of Old Domestic Life," 1936 Aug. 15 (Box 8, Folder M261)
    - [Kittrell] Normal and Industrial Institute, undated, 5 card photographs (Box 8, Folder M256)
    - [Lenoir] Art Studio of Amanda Clarke Blackwell, circa 1890s, black-and-white photograph (Box 7, Folder M258)
    - [Manteo] Monument to the Lost Colony, undated, card photograph (Box 8, Folder M259)
    - [New Bern] "The Tryon Palace," undated, black-and-white illustration (Box 8, Folder M260)
    - [North Carolina scenes], 1865 Mar. 11 -- 1936 Oct., 2 card photographs and 3 black-and-white photographs (Box 8, Folder M261)
    - [Raleigh] "Home of Marshall DeLancey Haywood," undated, postcard (Box 8, Folder M262)
    - [Raleigh] "Peace Institute," undated, card photograph (Box 8, Folder M263)
    - [Raleigh] Gen. Assembly House of Rep., 1915, black-and-white photo (Oversize-folder 11)
      Photos with corresponding names of each representative.
    - [Randolph County] "Free's School house," undated, card photograph (Box 8, Folder M264)
    - [Randolph County] "Hopewell Methodist Church," 1936 Oct., black-and-white photograph (Box 8, Folder M265)
      Not original church, but place where many... founders are buried.
    - [Roanoke] (unlabeled), no content (Oversize-folder 11)
    - [Roxboro] "Brooksdale Methodist Church," undated, black-and-white illustration (Box 8, Folder M266)
    - [Salem] "Church and Inspectors House," undated, black-and-white illustration (Box 40)
    - [Salem] "Moravian Buildings, Cemetery, etc.," undated, 9 card photographs (Box 8, Folder M268)
      Transferred from the John C. Kilgo Manuscripts.
    - [Salem] "Young Ladies Seminary," undated, black-and-white illustration (Box 40)
    - [Salem] Moravian Buildings, Cemetery, etc., undated, 3 card photographs (Box 44)
    - [Trinity] "Faculty and Students at Trinity High School," 1897, card photograph (Box 8, Folder M271)
    - [Wake Forest] "Johnson Medical Building," 1933, black-and-white photograph (Box 8, Folder M271a)
    - [Waynesville views and scenes], undated, 4 card photographs (Box 8, Folder M274)
    - [Waynesville] "Methodist Church, Parsonage, Public School," circa 1890s, black-and-white photographic illustration (Box 8, Folder M273)
    - [Wilmington] "First House Built in Wilmington, NC," 1855, engraving (Box 44)
    - [Wilmington] "The Old Cornelius Harnett Residence 'Hilton,'" 1800s, card photograph (Box 8, Folder M276)
    - [Wilmington] First Sewer Line Being Laid, early 1900s?, card photograph (Box 8, Folder M275)
    - Aerial photo of Durham Reservoir, undated, black-and-white photo (Oversize-folder 22)
    - Apex, 1975 July, 2 black-and-white photographs (Box 6, Folder M214)
    - Asheville, undated, 5 card photographs (Box 6, Folder M215.1)
    - Asheville, undated, 5 card photographs (Box 6, Folder M215.2)
    - Asheville, undated, 5 card photographs (Box 6, Folder M215.3)
    - Asheville, undated, 4 card photographs (Box 6, Folder M215.4)
    - Bennett Place, Durham 1925 and undated, 2 ink drawings (Box 44)
    - Civilian Conservation Corps, Camp Bob Reynolds, Topton, NC, 1934, black-and-white photo (Box 55)
    - Durham High School Class of 1956, 1956 May 4, black-and-white photograph (Box 7, Folder M236)
      Includes list of addresses of graduates as of 1956.
    - Durham Traction Co. Light and Power Plant, 1900s, black-and-white photograph (Box 7, Folder M244)
    - Durham: Eno River Park Plan, 1974, black-and-white illustration (Oversize-folder 14)
    - Durham: Photo of Baseball team, undated, black-and-white photo (Oversize-folder 21)
    - Durham: Photo of Basketball team, 1916-1917, black-and-white illustration (Oversize-folder 21)
    - Durham: Senior Class 1902, Trinity Park School, black-and-white photo (Oversize-folder 21)
      Handwritten note attached with names of each.
    - Durham: Senior Class T.P.S. [Trinity Park School], 1916, black-and-white photo (Box 56)
    - Durham: Trinity Park High School senior class, 1919, black-and-white photo (Oversize-folder 21)
    - Durham: Trinity Park High School. Faculty and Students, 1898-1899, black-and-white photo (Box 56)
    - Durham: Untitled class photograph, undated, black-and-white photo (Oversize-folder 21)
    - East Durham Concert Band, 1910 July 4, postcard (Box 8, Folder M252)
      Includes note from the donator and another note identifying a member of the band.
    - East Durham Methodist Episcopal Church, 1929, color illustration (Oversize-folder 11)
      Appears to be a concept drawing by architect.
    - Grady Literary Society, Trinity Park School, Durham NC, 1907, black-and-white photo (Oversize-folder 21)
    - Hickory Nut Falls N.C., 1858, color lithograph (Box 40)
    - Historical map of Randolph County, undated, color illustration (Oversize-folder 26)
    - Inauguration of Pres. WIlliam Preston Fein Nov. 19, 1910, black-and-white photo (Oversize-folder 34)
      Labelled as Fein, but actually is William Preston Few.
    - Inauguration of Pres. WIlliam Preston Fein Nov. 19, 1910, includes duplicate, 2 black-and-white photos (Oversize-folder 34)
    - Lakeview Mineral Spring, Moore County, 1900s, black-and-white photograph (Box 8, Folder M257)
    - [Laurinburg] Principal McDuffie and a group of his teachers, students, and buildings. Laurinburg Industrial Institute, 1931, black-and-white photo (Oversize-folder 17)
    - Mitchell's Falls, 1857, color lithograph (Box 40)
    - Nantucket Mills, Spray, NC, undated, black-and-white lithograph (Box 55)
    - New Bern, Harbor, 1864, black-and-white illustration (Oversize-folder 11)
    - North Carolina Mutual and Provident Association Buildings, Durham, 1900s, colored engraving (Box 47)
    - North Carolina Senators and Representatives in the Confederate Congress, 1861-1865, 1800s, black-and-white photograph (Box 40)
    - [North Carolina] Meth. Episc. Church, 1887, 2 black-and-white engravings (Oversize-folder 23)
      Title: "the North Carolina Conference." One of the items is fragile/tearing.
    - Salem Female Academy, undated, card photograph (Box 8, Folder M267)
    - Southern Public Utilities Office, Charlotte, NC, circa 1910-1925, black-and-white photo (Box 55)
    - Southwest View of Salem, undated, black-and-white illustration (Oversize-folder 11)
    - Swannanoa River, undated, card photograph (Box 8, Folder M270)
    - The Smoky Mountains, 1873 Homer Martin and R. Hinshelwood, artists, colored engraving (Box 8, Folder M269)
      New York: D. Appleton & Co.
    - Trinity Park School (Durham, N.C.) Class of 1910, 1913, 2 black-and-white photos (Oversize-folder 24)
      1913 item is broken.
    - Untitled group photo and duplicate, undated, 2 black-and-white photos (Oversize-folder 34)
    - Washington Duke's First Factory, Duke Homestead, circa 1870s, black-and-white photograph, albumen print (Box 39)
    - Watts Hospital campus, Durham, N.C., viewed from Broad and Club Blvd., circa 1920, black-and-white photograph (Box 58, Folder M1810)
    - Waynesville, NC, views and scenes, circa late 1800s, 5 large-format black-and-white photographs (Box 46)
      Groups in front of public buildings, one close-up picture of ox-cart with oxen. Description comes from title on archival folder; photographs are uncaptioned and undated.
    - Waynesville, undated, Meriwether and Williams, photographers, card photograph (Box 8, Folder M272)
  - Ohio, 40
    - Episcopal Log-Church (in the woods) near Gambier, engraving (Box 9, Folder M277)
    - Log House in Ohio, engraving (Box 9, Folder M277)
  - Panama, 41
    - Atlantic entrance [2], 1913, black-and-white photo (Oversize-folder 12)
      Panoramic photograph. Please handle with care.
    - Atlantic entrance, 1913, black-and-white photo (Oversize-folder 12)
    - Bas Obispo cut, 1913, black-and-white photo (Oversize-folder 12)
    - Cathedral Plaza, 1913, black-and-white photo (Oversize-folder 12)
    - Coccoli lake site, 1913, black-and-white photo (Oversize-folder 12)
    - Colon, 1913, black-and-white photo (Oversize-folder 12)
    - Cucharacha Slide - Culebra cut, 1913, black-and-white photo (Oversize-folder 12)
    - Culebra cut - at Empire, 1913, black-and-white photo (Oversize-folder 12)
    - Culebra cut, 1913, black-and-white photo (Oversize-folder 12)
    - Dredges, 1913, black-and-white photo (Oversize-folder 12)
    - Gatun Lake, 1913, black-and-white photo (Oversize-folder 12)
    - Gatun Locks - Emergency Dams, 1913, black-and-white photo (Oversize-folder 12)
    - Gatun Locks - lake entrance, 1913, black-and-white photo (Oversize-folder 12)
    - Gatun Locks - lower levels, 1913, black-and-white photo (Oversize-folder 12)
    - Gatun Locks - north approach, 1913, black-and-white photo (Oversize-folder 12)
    - Gatun Locks - north approach[2], 1913, black-and-white photo (Oversize-folder 12)
    - Gatun Locks - upper level, 1913, black-and-white photo (Oversize-folder 12)
    - Miraflores locks - lower level, 1913, black-and-white photo (Oversize-folder 12)
    - Old Sea Wall - Panama City, 1913, black-and-white photo (Oversize-folder 12)
    - Panama City, 1913, black-and-white photo (Oversize-folder 12)
    - Pedro Miguel locks, 1913, black-and-white photo (Oversize-folder 12)
  - Pennsylvania, 42
    - [Gettysburg views], undated, 25 black-and-white photographs (Box 9, Folder M279)
    - [Philadelphia] "The East Prospect of the City of Philadelphia in the Province of Pennsylvania," 1700s, engraving (Box 9, Folder M281)
      Photocopy. From "Sketches of the Life and Correspondence of Gen. N. Greene."
    - [Philadelphia] "The East Prospect of the City of Philadelphia in the Province of Pennsylvania," 1700s, engraving (Box 61)
    - [Philadelphia] University of Pennsylvania, 1765, undated, card photograph (Box 9, Folder M282)
    - 100th Anniversary of the Independence of the United States, 1876, black-and-white illustration (Oversize-folder 11)
      Poster showing centennial exhibition buildings.
    - Headwaters of the Juniata, Alleghany Mountains, Pensylvania [sic], after painting by Thomas Cole, 1831, black-and-white engraving (Box 58, Folder M1811)
    - Philadelphia, 1800s, engraving (Box 9, Folder M280)
    - Pittsburgh in 1790, color engraving (Oversize-folder 17)
      Taken from the south side of the Monongahela river.
    - Reunion at Gettysburg, circa 1898, 2 black-and-white photographs (Box 9, Folder M278)
  - Peru, 43
    - [Lifestyles of Peru], circa 1900, 8 black-and-white photographs (Box 9, Folder M283.1)
    - [Lifestyles of Peru], circa 1900, 6 black-and-white photographs (Box 9, Folder M283.2)
  - Philippines, 44
    - [Cagayan Province] Album de la Cagayan Province, 1900s, 17 card photographs (Box 9, Folder M285)
      The album is comprised of 17 photographs.
    - [Manila and other subjects], circa 1890s, 28 color paintings (Box 9, Folder M286)
    - [Masbate] Officials at Masbate, undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 9, Folder M284)
    - Photographs of Philippine Library, circa 1913-1914, black-and-white photograph (Box 38)
      9 black-and-white photographs; one mounted, rest loose
  - Poland, 45
    - Karkow, Lezajsk, Stalowa Wola, and countryside, undated, 5 postcards (Box 9, Folder M287)
  - Russia, 46
    - Russisches Blockaus..., undated, color illustration (Box 40)
  - Scotland, 47
    - Abbotsford, undated, engraving (Box 9, Folder M288)
    - Edinburgh Castle, undated, 6 engravings (Box 9, Folder M289)
  - Siam (Thailand), 48
    - Ayuthia, undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 9, Folder M290)
  - Slovakia
    - Pressburg [Bratislava, Slovakia], 19th century?, black-and-white engraving (Box 63, Folder 4)
      Once part of Austrian Empire. Engraving by Schmidt.
  - South Carolina, 49
    - "Appearance of Fort Sumter on Sunday Afternoon - August 23d 1863...," Charleston, S.C., undated, lithograph (Box 44)
      Drawn from nature by W.T. Crone
    - [Charleston Ruins], undated, card photograph (Box 40)
      From "Lowdermilk's Book Store, Washington D.C. 1966."
    - [Charleston Views], 1900s, 14 black-and-white photographs (Box 10, Folder M296)
    - [Charleston] "Charleston, S.C. and Its Vicinity," 1863, engraving (Box 10, Folder M292)
    - [Charleston] "East Battery," undated, W. Courtenay Corcoran, artist, charcoal sketch (Box 10, Folder M294)
      Photocopy of original.
    - [Charleston] "St. Phillip's Church, Charleston, S.C.," 1897, heliotype (Box 44)
      Erected 1723. Burnt 1835. From an engraving in Library of H.P. Archer, Esq., John P. Hall, delt.
    - [Charleston] "Sunset View of Fort Sumter Before the Bombardment," 1800s, engraving (Box 10, Folder M295)
    - [Charleston] "Views of Charleston, the Capital of South Carolina," undated, 3 paper prints (Box 44)
    - [Charleston] Citadel, undated, card photograph (Box 40)
    - [Charleston] College of Charleston, undated, card photograph (Box 40)
    - [Charleston] Earthquake Scenes, 1886 Sept., 28 card photographs (Box 10, Folder M293)
    - [Charleston] Female Orphan Asylum, undated, card photograph (Box 40)
    - [Charleston] Hiberman Society Hall, undated, card photograph (Box 40)
    - [Charleston] In the Institute Hall, the ordinance of secession was signed Dec. 20, 1860, late 1800s?, black-and-white photograph (Box 58, Folder M1821)
      Mounted on thick card. Shows the Institute Building exterior.
    - [Charleston] Mills House, undated, card photograph (Box 40)
    - [Charleston] Ruins in Charleston, undated, card photograph (Box 40)
    - [Charleston] S.C. Interstate and West Indian Exposition, 1901-1902, 6 card photographs (Box 40)
    - [Charleston] S.C. Interstate and West Indian Exposition, 1901-1902, 7 card photographs (Box 40)
    - [Charleston] The French Protestant Church, 1888, lithograph (Box 44)
      Transferred from the Marmaduke Floyd Collection
    - [Charleston] Wharf, Ruins of Circular Church and Judge King Mansion, 1800s, 3 card photographs (Box 10, Folder M297)
    - [Charleston] William Washington Home, South Battery, undated, postcard (Box 10, Folder M298)
    - [Morris Island] "Attack on Fort Wagner," undated, Thomas Nast painter, lithograph (Box 10, Folder M301)
      One stereograph removed to S27 in the Stereographs Series.
    - [Orangeburg] Claflin University, circa 1888, 13 card photographs (Box 10, Folder M302)
    - [South Carolina buildings], undated, 7 black-and-white photographs (Box 10, Folder M303)
    - [Spartanburg -- Wofford college students], undated, card photograph (Box 10, Folder M304)
      Group picture of class in which Robert Few and William Few were members.
    - A View of Charles Town, the Capitol of South Carolina, 1776, reproduction from 1971, black-and-white engraving (Oversize-folder 38)
      Reproduced from original engraving, 1971.
    - An exact prospect of Charles Town, the Metropolis of the Province of South Carolina, 1882, black-and-white engraving (Oversize-folder 55)
    - Arx Carolina, undated, color illustration (Oversize-folder 38)
    - Beaufort, undated, 56 black-and-white photographs (Box 9, Folder M291)
      These photographs were compiled for "Tales of Beaufort" by Nell S. Graydon -- Beaufort Bookshop, Inc. Beaufort, S.C., 1963.
    - Charleston, S.C., 1800s, color lithograph (Box 41)
    - Dry goods warehouse, Bancroft Betts and Marshall and Browning and Lemon. Charleston So. Ca., undated, black-and-white engraving (Box 56)
      Exterior view.
    - Dry goods warehouse, Bancroft Betts and Marshall and Browning and Lemon. Charleston So. Ca., undated, black-and-white engraving (Box 56)
      Interior view.
    - Fort Sumter 1860, W. Courtenay Corcoran, artist, charcoal sketch (Box 10, Folder M299)
    - Lynching of Nicholas S. Hill, Jr., at Isle of Palms, New Year's Day, 1900, black-and-white photo (Box 56)
    - Main Building -- Erskine College, Due West, undated, card photograph (Box 10, Folder M300)
    - S.C. Print Press Association, at Myrtle Beach, SC, undated, black-and-white photo (Oversize-folder 55)
    - To His Excellency James Glen Esq., 1700s, engraving (Box 44)
    - Untitled photo of a beach, undated, black-and-white photo (Box 57)
  - South Dakota, 50
    - Mount Rushmore Memorial, circa 1938, 6 black-and-white photographs (Box 41)
      Two of these photographs are from the Harry A. Slattery Papers.
  - Sweden, 51
    - Koniglicherpallast in Stockholm, 1700s, engraving (Box 10, Folder M305)
  - Syria, 52
    - Views from Bible Lands, undated, 14 engravings (Box 2, Folder M79)
      Engravings are part of a small book; included are a title page, index, and background information on the engraved pictures. Includes Antioch, Damascus, Ephesus, Jaffa, Laodicea, Nablous, Palmyra, Pergamus, Philadelphia, Smyrna, Souk Barrada, the Barrada at Damascus, Tarsus, and Thyatira.
  - Tennessee, 53
    - [Anderson] "Military Post Anderson, Tenn.," 1800s, color lithograph (Box 40)
    - [Cowan] "View of Military Post Cowan, Tennessee.," 1800s, color lithograph (Box 40)
    - [Franklin] "Carter Cotton Gin and Screw - morning after battle Nov. 30, 1864," 1864 Nov. 30, black-and-white photograph (Box 10, Folder M309)
      Photograph of an original pencil sketch.
    - [Memphis] River steamer leading cotton, undated, card photograph (Box 10, Folder M310)
    - [Nashville -- views of the hermitage], undated, 9 black-and-white photographs and 1 map (Box 11, Folder M313)
    - [Nashville] "The Hermitage," ca. 1943, black-and-white photograph (Box 10, Folder M312)
    - Chattanooga, 1865, 3 black-and-white photographs (Box 38)
    - Chattanooga, Lookout Mountain and Battlefield, undated, album, souvenir (Box 10, Folder M306)
    - Coat of Arms of Tennessee, undated, engraving (Box 10, Folder M307)
    - Johnson City, undated, black-and-white illustrations (Oversize-folder 11)
      Group of printed photos of Johnson city from 1890, relates to Daughters of the American Revolution conference, 1923.
    - Mocassin Bend and Lookout Battlefield, undated, card photograph (Box 10, Folder M311)
    - Nashville -- views of The Hermitage, undated, 18 black-and-white photographs (Box 10, Folder M313)
    - The Falls of Fall Creek Near Smithville, Tenn., undated, lithograph (Box 10, Folder M308)
  - Texas, 54
    - [San Antonio] San Jose -- built 1718, undated, card photograph (Box 11, Folder M314)
  - Virginia, 55
    - [Alexandria] Stabler's Drug Warehouse, undated, one card photograph and one black-and-white photograph (Box 11, Folder M315)
    - [Arlington] Soldiers' Graves, undated, paper photograph (Box 11, Folder M316)
    - [Brunswick County] Ebenezer Academy, undated, card photograph (Box 11, Folder M317)
    - [Charlottesville] The University of Virginia, 1831 Dec. 1, engraving (Box 11, Folder M318)
    - [Fredericksburg] Home of Mary Washington, undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 11, Folder M320)
    - [Jamestown] "Scenes at the Jamestown Exposition.", volume of photographs, 124 pages (Box 11, Folder M322)
    - [Jamestown] Remains of Confederate breastworks on Jamestown Exposition Grounds, undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 11, Folder M322)
    - [Mount Vernon] Washington's Room and Bed on Which He Died, undated, card photograph (Box 11, Folder M324)
    - [Richmond] "Battle Abbey of the South," undated, black-and-white photograph (Box 11, Folder M327)
      Formerly the Confederate Memorial Institute, now the headquarters of the Virginia Historical Society.
    - [Richmond] "The White House of the Confederacy, Richmond, Va.," undated, black-and-white illustration (Box 40)
    - [Richmond] Capitol of Virginia, 1850, engraving (Box 11, Folder M328)
    - [Richmond] Libby Prison, undated, card photograph (Box 11, Folder M329)
    - [Richmond] Pratt's Castle, undated, card photograph (Box 11, Folder M330)
    - [The former Falls Church], undated, card photograph (Box 11, Folder M319)
    - [Westmoreland] "Stratford, The Birthplace of Gen. Robert E. Lee, Westmoreland Co., Va.," undated, 2 black-and-white illustrations (Box 40)
      The smaller illustration is a photogravure, a special method of photo-reproduction, of the larger original. The large original illustration has a negative available.
    - Battle of Yorktown, undated, black-and-white illustration (Oversize-folder 11)
      Photo of painting.
    - Hot Springs, Bath Co., Va., undated, card photograph (Box 11, Folder M321)
    - Monticello -- Home of Thomas Jefferson, 1900s, color illustration (Box 40)
    - Mount Vernon, undated, 3 card photographs (Box 11, Folder M323)
    - Norfolk, Portsmouth, Va., 1800s, engraving (Box 11, Folder M325)
    - Richmond from the James, 1800s, color engraving (Box 40)
    - Richmond Monuments photo album, undated, album (Box 48)